## PHILIP A. FAIRHURST MINONDO

Madrid, Spain (+34) 661 014 983 | philip.fm@student.ie.edu | www.linkedin.com/in/philipfairhurst/

Work Qualified: USA / Guatemala

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven multicultural professional with continuous improvement mindset focused on process optimization by leveraging data and technology. 8+ years' experience in International Supply Chain, 3+ were dedicated to digital transformation, Business Data Analytics, and process improvement. Critical thinker with experience in Power BI, SAP, and systems integration.

#### **EDUCATION**

IE BUSINESS SCHOOL MADRID, SPAIN

Dual Degree: International MBA + Masters Big Data and Business Analytics

JAN. 2021 - JUL. 2022 (EXPECTED)

• IE<sup>3</sup> Collaboration Award

MIAMI DADE COLLEGE MIAMI, USA

Bachelor of Applied Science: Supply Chain Management

SEP. 2014 - MAY 2018

Sigma Beta Delta Honor Society

Propeller Club (Supply Chain Club)

University of Colorado Boulder, USA

Bachelor of Arts: Environmental Design SEP. 2007 - MAY 2012

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>L'Oreal – Travel Retail Americas (TRAM)</u>
TRAM is responsible for the procurement, distribution, and sales of products in the Travel Retail market for the western hemisphere.

MIAMI, USA

JUL. 2018 - DEC. 2020

## Supply Chain Performance Analyst – Local Business Expert

Main business contact for Physical Distribution department and cross-departmental projects.

• Transformed analytics processes in TRAM supply chain department by leading design, integration, and implementation of Power BI Analytics, resulting in 60+ hours per month in workload reduction and +\$200k cost savings opportunities.

- Collaborated with Travel Retail counterparts to create global standardized Power BI reporting tools used by TR affiliates (TR-HQ, EMEA, APAC, AME).
- Decreased market product deviation by 20% by coordinating a multi departmental task force aimed at minimizing product diversion into non desired markets and developing tools to automate and simplify process.
- First member in TRAM Operations to incorporate Power BI tools and Power Queries to optimize Business Operations.

## Supply & Demand Planner – Active Cosmetics Division & Professional Products Division

JUL. 2017 - JUL. 2018

Led and managed projects focused on creating and/or improving Supply Chain processes and efficiencies. Analyzed, reported, and communicated TRAM Supply Chain KPI's to affiliate's key stakeholders and Global Travel Retail Supply Chain Operations Management.

- Developed and improved tools and processes to efficiently streamline complexities of stock management, product assortment, and internal alignment, resulting in a 20% workload reduction.
- Managed stock for 300+ SKU's and achieved highest historical forecast accuracy in 4 years, +10.7% vs 2<sup>nd</sup> highest.
- Launched multiple products. Vichy Mineral 89: face hydration market #1 product (2018 -2020).

#### OSPREY S.C.S (AGRIBUSINESS ENTREPRENEURIAL VENTURE)

MIAMI, USA

#### Supply Chain Consultant

MAR. 2016 - JUL. 2017

- Lowered lead times by 20% and developed new supplier and distribution channels, resulting in increased produce freshness and diminished waste-produce.
- Strong emphasis on inventory control and planning to keep optimum quality on 100,000 lbs. of weekly produce.

## PREFERRED FREEZER SERVICES (TRANSPORTATION & LOGISTICS, +\$300M, WWW.LINEAGELOGISTICS.COM)

MIAMI, USA

## **Warehouse Operations Assistant**

May 2014 - Mar. 2016

- Sustained +99% accurate inventory using "live feed" Wi-fi software in a 17,000 pallet-position, 28 million lb. freezer warehouse. (7.1M Cu. Ft.).
- Assisted managing warehouse operations by prioritizing tasks, allocating resources, and taking effective decisions to maintain daily turnover of +80 container loads without incident or delay.

## **OPORTUNIDADES ALTERNAS S.A. (PROCUREMENT & EXPORT ENTREPRENEURIAL VENTURE)**

GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA

Sourcing and Operations Manager

Jun. 2013 - May 2014

• Achieved \$800,000 in sales while increasing supplier base by 250% resulting in 20% cost reduction.

# DESARROLLOS TINOCO ABRIL Y ASOCIADOS (ARCHITECTURE & DESIGN)

GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA OCT. 2012 - JUN. 2013

3D Draftsman

Power BI Analytics, SAP, Excel (Queries, Power Tools, etc.)

### LANGUAGES

IT SKILLS

English (native); Spanish (native)